[
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 1",
        "number": "01",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Green, of snow or nature,\nIt highlights a beautiful figure,\nOf math or French,\nYou are the last one.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Class"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 2",
        "number": "02",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "This vehicle is not next to the first,\nBut you mustn't miss it, as it is the last.\nIt is also a value equal to a year,\nAnd thanks to it, sheep are separated.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Broom"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 3",
        "number": "03",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It can give wings to throats,\nIt qualifies the iron we forge,\nThe decoration of lips,\nIt colors our emotions.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Red"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 4",
        "number": "04",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It is extraordinary at sea,\nWithout tomorrow and ephemeral.\nTo venture into it could be tragic,\nOn Fort Boyard, it is epic.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Adventure"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 5",
        "number": "05",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It is a crown without a king,\nWhose pulp cannot be drunk,\nAt the top of the peaks located,\nIt is unfortunate to tear it off.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Tooth"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 6",
        "number": "06",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It is a long sign full of elegance,\nIt manages sounds and silences.\nIt makes a difference in shades.\nWithout them, intransigence sets in.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Nuance"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 7",
        "number": "07",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "We keep it without failing,\nSo radiant for pleasure,\nA sister was thus named,\nBeware of the plumber's one.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Smile"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 8",
        "number": "08",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Order where eloquence reigns,\nA master king of defense.\nFrom the chair to the ladder,\nIt is an essential support.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Bar"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 9",
        "number": "09",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It is hidden in your ear,\nAssociated with madness,\nA piano has more than one,\nBe careful of its shark.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Hammer"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2022 - Show 10",
        "number": "10",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "At the top of the masts once perched,\nIts function is to watch,\nNecessary for airports,\nWe find it at the top of the fort.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Lookout"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 1",
        "number": "01",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Tiny amount,\nIt is said to be easy.\nIn plural, it is linked\nTo a very large reptile.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Tear"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 2",
        "number": "02",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It makes cries,\nTears, howls,\nIt is a disease,\nA torture for teeth.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Rabies"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 3",
        "number": "03",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "Every year, it changes incessantly,\nWhether critical or ungrateful,\nFrom flower to wisdom,\nIts mystery remains.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Age"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 4",
        "number": "04",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Worn on the belt,\nHaving it makes one happy,\nIt is made in the hair,\nIt is peeled to eat.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Banana"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 5",
        "number": "05",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "We find it in Brittany,\nWhere they love to write their name.\nIt is a beautiful bowl,\nOne can drink soup from it.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Bowl"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 6",
        "number": "06",
        "type": "After",
        "question": "Cyril Gossbo was the prettiest,\nBefore being thrown away.\nAnd in the playground,\nIt can be made of cloth.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Doll"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 7",
        "number": "07",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "Cookie anchored in our memories,\nSweetness of childhood long and sugary,\nIn this place worthy of receiving,\nMany secrets were entrusted.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Boudoir"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 8",
        "number": "08",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "We see it from beach to beach,\nIt competes with the clouds.\nWe donâ€™t eat from its pine,\nIt is related to the parasol.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Parasol"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 9",
        "number": "09",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It is often foreign,\nAnd very useful for traveling.\nThey are legendary words\nThat a man, a king invented.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Motto"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Show 10",
        "number": "10",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It is deprived of its half,\nIsolated at the top of the page,\nIt is associated with the orphan.\nBlack, it injects its venom.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Widow"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Episode 11",
        "number": "11",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Whether mad or divine,\nAngry or cherubic,\nIt evokes so much in its name,\nAll the flames and passions.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "Love"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2023 - Episode 12",
        "number": "12",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "There is only a half-step,\nTo make it minor.\nIn conjugation,\nIt's a major asset.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Chord"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 1",
        "number": "01",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "In the air or asked for,\nTo have just one is to swear.\nOne can give it as well,\nAnd holding it is to commit.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Word"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 2",
        "number": "02",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "On a rough sea,\nIt does back-and-forth movements\nLike on flattened dough.\nIn painting, it is commonly used.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Roller"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 3",
        "number": "03",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "By day or night,\nIt feeds on a trumpet,\nIn the swirling air.\nA little of it is threatening.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Butterfly"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 4",
        "number": "04",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It's a linking word\nThat precedes certain nouns.\nPresent in dust,\nIt is elementary.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Particle"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 5",
        "number": "05",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It is sure or common,\nAnd the Fort is one.\nIt is a complement,\nThis neighbor of whiting.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Place"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 6",
        "number": "06",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "These two sisters diving into the dark,\nGaining weight when night falls,\nThey are the setting for our two globes,\nTheir makeup doesn't guide any sailor.\nWho are they?",
        "answer": "The Eyelids"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 7",
        "number": "07",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "Used to cascades,\nIt does nothing without gravity,\nLocated at the end of the tale,\nPronounce it to avoid it.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Fall"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 8",
        "number": "08",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It is in the sky or in the wind,\nOne we take or suspend,\nAnd from the thief to the bird,\nIt is often judged very high.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Flight"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 9",
        "number": "09",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "In printing, this sure value\nIs well present in writing.\nNot always good or bad.\nIt is a whole set of traits.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Character"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 10",
        "number": "10",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "Not rhythmic and jerky,\nIt can be musical.\nBut becomes quickly hellish,\nFor the worker's labor.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Cadence"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 11",
        "number": "11",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Vast stretch of land,\nParadise for the solidarity\nIt's a beach devoid of water,\nIts vessel is always bumpy.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Desert"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 12",
        "number": "12",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It is sometimes magical,\nOften mathematical,\nTo roll fast and well,\nYou need the number 1.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Formula"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2021 - Episode 13",
        "number": "13",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It is a precious link of a stronghold,\nAn illustrious figure who comes and goes.\nIt is a frame made of somewhat thick cardboard.\nNothing resists this key.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Master Key"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 1",
        "number": "01",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Alpine or Nordic,\nIt is a telephone tool.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Receiver"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 2",
        "number": "02",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It is sometimes a transaction,\nOr just a conversation.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Exchange"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 3",
        "number": "03",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "Its star doesn't shine,\nIts horse doesn't gallop,\nIts spider doesn't sting,\nIts elephant doesn't trumpet,\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Sea"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 4",
        "number": "04",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "They are from a country\nRhyme with magic,\nSweet festive donuts,\nThere are seven in the world.\nWho are they?",
        "answer": "The Wonders"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 5",
        "number": "05",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "In nice sheets sometimes,\nIts train can cause fear.\nNever lacking in spirit,\nIt appears when night comes.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Ghost"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 6",
        "number": "06",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It amuses us, entertains us\nAnd can be worth less than a candle,\nIf it needs to be calmed,\nWe must respect its rule.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Game"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 7",
        "number": "07",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "It is often quite tense,\nAnd we avoid it when we see it.\nOf larks, the mirror,\nBe careful of its jaws.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Trap"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 8",
        "number": "08",
        "type": "After",
        "question": "Whether a quarter or half,\nIt is a silence it translates.\nAs long as it is not the last,\nWe can always push it.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Sigh"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 9",
        "number": "09",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "Rather pretty, well made up,\nIt also adorns the wounded finger,\nWhether made of wax or sound,\nIts face is without expression.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Doll"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 10",
        "number": "10",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "Like wrinkles on water,\nFrom a shock, they descend to zero.\nFrom the ground to the radio,\nThey follow the microphone.\nWho are they?",
        "answer": "The Waves"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 11",
        "number": "11",
        "type": "Key",
        "question": "It requires no effort,\nIs difficult to seize,\nAnd it will never return.\nIt is formed in an instant.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Moment"
    },
    {
        "emission": "Fort Boyard 2020 - Episode 12",
        "number": "12",
        "type": "Clue",
        "question": "The fact that it is empty,\nIs a failure. It always falls.\nThe secret of success,\nIs to throw it in the back.\nWho is it?",
        "answer": "The Hole"
    }
]